In this video, we're going to talk about sub typing another important idea in cool
在这个视频中，我们将讨论在酷中输入另一个重要的想法
and other object oriented languages. Let's begin by taking a look at the typing rule
以及其他面向对象的语言。让我们从查看键入规则开始
for let with initialization. So last time we looked at the let rule, but didn't have
FOR LET WITH INTIZATION。上一次我们看了LET规则，但是没有
the initializers. Let's just see how adding the initializer right here changes
初始化器。让我们来看看在这里添加初始化器会有什么变化
things. So what's going to happen here? Well first of all, notice that the body of
一些事情。那么这里会发生什么呢？首先，请注意，
the rule is almost the same. So We type check E1 in an environment where X has
规则几乎是一样的。因此，我们在X具有以下特性的环境中键入check E1
type T0. The type is declared to have in the let And all the other variables have
键入T0。该类型在let中声明为Have，而所有其他变量都具有
whatever types O gives them And we can add some type T1, and that'll be the type of
无论O给他们什么类型，我们可以添加一些类型T1，这就是
the whole thing. So this piece Right here is exactly the same as before. So what's
整件事。所以这里的这一块和以前一模一样。那么什么是
new is this line of where we type check the initializer. And so how does that
新的是我们在其中键入check the initializer的这一行。那么如何做到这一点呢？
work? Well, first of all, under the assumptions o we type check e zero, we get
工作?首先，在假设我们键入check e 0的情况下，我们得到
some type t zero. And this is really an aside from the main point, but notice that
一些类型t0。这确实偏离了主要观点，但请注意
we use the environment o, in particular x. The new definition of X is not available
我们使用环境o，特别是x。X的新定义不可用
in E0, so if E0 uses the name X that means it uses the name of some other X that's
在E0中，如果E0使用名称X，这意味着它使用某个其他X的名称，即
defined outside Of the lead because we didn't include a, this definition of X in
定义在销售线索之外，因为我们没有包括一个，这个X的定义在
the environment for type checking E0. All right now, but the main point a, thing I
类型检查环境E0。好的，但是主要的一点，事情是
want to point oh I'm a sly, is that easier or here has type zero which is exactly
想指出哦，我是个狡猾的人，是比较容易呢，还是这里有类型0，就是
same type as X, and that's a requirement of this rule, it says that E0 has to have
与X相同的类型，这是此规则的要求，它规定E0必须具有
the same type as X, and that's actually fairly weak of because it's really a, no
与X相同的类型，这实际上是相当弱的，因为它真的是一个，不
problem if E0 has a type which is a subtype of T0, a. T zero can hold any
问题：如果E0的类型是T0的子类型，则.t0可以容纳任何
sub-type of T zero, that would be absolutely fine. But here we've limited
亚型的T0，那绝对没问题。但在这里我们限制了
ourselves to only allowing initializers that exactly match the type of X. So we
我们只允许与X的类型完全匹配的初始值设定项。因此，我们
can do better if we introduce the sub typing relation on classes. And the most
如果我们在类上引入子类型关系，可以做得更好。最重要的是
obvious form of sub typing is that if X is a class and inherits directly from, from
子类型的明显形式是，如果X是一个类并且直接从继承，则从
Y, meaning there's a line in the code that says X inherits from Y. Then x should be a
表示代码中有一行X继承自Y，那么x应该是一个
sub type o f Y. And furthermore this relationship is transitive. So if x is a
子类型的Y，而且这个关系是传递的。所以如果x是一个
sub type of y, and y is a sub type of z, then x is a sub type of z. And finally as
y的子类型，y是z的子类型，那么x是z的子类型。
you might expect, it's also reflexive, so every class is a sub type of itself. And
您可能会想到，它也是反射性的，所以每个类都是其自身的子类型。和
using sub typing, we can write out a better version of the let rule with
使用子类型，我们可以用以下命令写出更好版本的let规则
initialization. So once again, the body, the, the part of the rule that deals with
初始化。所以再一次，身体，规则中涉及到的部分
the body of the let is exactly the same as before, so let's not look at that, and.
LET的正文和以前完全一样，所以我们不看了，和。
Now what we're going to do is we're gonna type check E0 and we get some type T0 out,
现在我们要做的是键入check E0，然后取出一些类型T0，
and then T0 now is only required to be a sub-type of T, so this here is another
然后T0现在只需要是T的一个子类型，所以这里是另一个
hypothesis. And it just says that T zero has to be a sub type of T and what is T,
假设。它只是说T0必须是T的一个子类型，什么是T，
well T is now the type that X is declared to be. So this allows E zero to have a
好的，T现在是X声明的类型。所以这使得E0可以有一个
type that's different from the type of X, and the only issue here is that more
类型与X的类型不同，这里唯一的问题是更多
programs will type check with this rule in the previous one. The previous rule that
程序将在前一个规则中键入check with this Rule。前面的规则是
we had was certainly correct, any program that compiled with that rule, would run
我们肯定是正确的，任何用该规则编译的程序都可以运行
correctly, but this is a more permissive and still correct rule. More programs will
正确，但这是一个更宽松且仍然正确的规则。将有更多的计划
compile and type check correctly, using this rule. Sub-typing shows up in a number
使用此规则正确编译并键入检查。子键入在数字中显示
of places in the cool type system. Here's the rule for assignment, which is in many
凉爽类型系统中的位置。下面是赋值的规则，这在许多情况下都存在
ways similar to the rule for let. So, how does an assignment work, well on the left
方式类似于LET的规则。那么，任务是如何工作的呢？
hand side is a variable and the right hand side is an expression, we're gonna
手边是一个变量，右手边是一个表达式，我们将
evaluate the expression and assign whatever value we get back. To the
对表达式求值，然后分配我们得到的任何值。发送到
variable on the left-hand side And so what how is this type-checked? Well, first of
变量放在左边，那么这个类型是如何检查的呢？嗯，首先，
all, we have to look up the type of X in the environment, and we discovered it has
总之，我们必须在环境中查找X的类型，我们发现它有
some type T0 And then we type-check E1 in the same environment. So the set of
一些类型为T0，然后我们在相同的环境中键入检查E1。所以这组
variables here is not changing. And so we type-check E1 environment O, and we get
这里的变量没有改变。所以我们输入检查E1环境O，我们得到
some type T1. And now what has to be true for this assignment to be correct? Well it
某种类型的T1。现在，什么必须是正确的，才能使这项任务正确呢？嗯，它
has to possible for X to hold the value of type T1. So X's type T0 has to be a super
X必须有可能保存T1类型的值。所以X的T0型必须是超级的
type, has to be bigger than the type of T1. So, if this [inaudible] Is satisfied,
类型，必须大于T1的类型。所以，如果这个(听不见的)得到满足，
then the assignment is correct. Another example that uses sub-typing is the rule
那么任务是正确的。另一个使用子类型的示例是规则
for attribute initialization which except for the scope for identifiers is very,
对于除了标识符的范围之外的属性初始化是非常重要的，
very similar to the rule for normal assignments. So recall what a class looks
与正常作业的规则非常相似。所以回想一下班级是什么样子的
like, you can declare a class in Cool and it has at the top level some set of
例如，您可以在Cool中声明一个类，它在顶层有一些
attributes and methods. And what does an attribute Definition look like. Well it
属性和方法。属性定义是什么样子。嗯，它
looks like one of these things. It's, a variable declared to some type and you can
看起来像是这些东西之一。它是一个声明为某种类型的变量，您可以
have an initializer on the right hand side. And so in what environment then is
在右手边有一个初始值设定项。那么在什么样的环境下
this initializer type checked? Well, its type checked in this special environment O
是否检查此初始值设定项类型？嗯，它的类型是在这个特殊的环境中检查的。
sub c which just consists of the types of all the attributes that are declared in
SUB c，它只是由在中声明的所有属性的类型组成。
class c. So this mean we have to make a pass over the class definition, pull out
类c。这意味着我们必须通过类定义，拉出
all the attribute definitions, all the names of the variables and their types,
所有属性定义、所有变量名称及其类型，
build an environment. That [inaudible] all that information, and then we can type
营造环境。所有这些信息都是[听不见的]，然后我们就可以打字了
check the initialize rs because remember the initializer for an attribute can refer
检查初始化rs，因为记住属性的初始值设定项可以引用
to any of the initialize rs for the class. So, let's take a look at how this works.
类的任何初始化RS。那么，让我们来看看它是如何工作的。
First we look up the type of X in the environment. That's sum type T O. Now we
首先，我们在环境中查找X的类型。那是SUM类型的T。现在我们
type check E1 in the same environment. That's sum type T1. And then just as with
在同一环境中键入check E1。这是和类型T1。然后，就像
assignment T1 needs to be a subset or a subtype of the type T O. Now we come to
赋值T1需要是类型T的子集或子类型。
another interesting example how we type check If and Else. And the important thing
另一个有趣的例子是我们如何键入check if和Else。重要的是
about If and Else is that when we're doing type checking we don't know which branch
关于IF和ELSE的问题是，当我们进行类型检查时，我们不知道哪个分支
is going to be taken, we don't know whether the program is going to execute E1
，我们不知道程序是否会执行E1
or E2, and in general actually this statement may or If this expression may
或E2，通常实际上此语句可以或如果此表达式可以
execute multiple times doing a run of the program, in sometimes it may execute only
执行多次运行程序，有时可能只执行
one, other times it may execute it two. And so what that means that the resulting
一次，另一些时候，它可能执行两次。所以这意味着由此产生的
type of am If and Else is either the type of E1 or the type E2 and we don't. Know a
AM的类型IF和ELSE要么是E1的类型，要么是E2的类型，我们不知道。
compile time, which one is going to be . So the best we can do. Is to say the type
编译时间，哪一个将是。所以我们能做的就是。就是说这种类型
of entire if then else is the smallest super type larger than either e1 or e2 The
如果整个if则是比e1或e2大的最小的超类型，则
need to compute an upper bound over two or more types comes up often enough that
需要计算两个或更多类型的上界的次数足够频繁，以至于
we're going to give the operation a special name. We'll call it the LUB or
我们要给这次行动起个特别的名字。我们会叫它Lub或者
least upper bound of X and Y. And the least upper bound of X and Y is going to
X和Y的最小上界，以及X和Y的最小上界将
be Z if Z is an upper bound, so meaning it's bigger than both X and Y, and also if
如果Z是一个上界，那么就是Z，也就是说它比X和Y都大，而且如果
it is the least among all possible upper bounds. So what this line here says, is
在所有可能的上限中，它是最小的。所以这条线说的是，
that there is some other Z prime that's bigger than X and Y. Well then z has to be
还有一些比X和Y更大的Z素数，那么z必须是
smaller than z prime. So z is the least, if z smallest of all the possible upper
比z素数小。所以z是最小的，如果z是所有可能的上限中最小的
bounds of x and y. And in Cool, and in most object oriented languages, the least
x和y的界限。在Cool和大多数面向对象语言中，至少
upper bound of two types is just their least common ancestor in the inheritance
两种类型的上界只是它们在继承中的最小共同祖先
tree. So typically, the inheritance tree is rooted at object or some similarly
树。因此，通常情况下，继承树的根是对象或一些类似的
named class that incorporates, that includes all possible classes of the
合并的命名类，它包括
program. And then there's some kind of a hierarchy which is a tree, That descends
程序。然后是某种层次结构，它是一棵树，从下往下
from object, and, and if I want to find the least upper bound of two types, say
从Object，并且，如果我想找出两种类型中的最小上界，比方说
this type and this type, I just have to walk back through the tree until I find
这种类型和这种类型，我只需要往回走一遍树，直到我找到
their least common ancestor. And so, in this case, if I pick these two types out
他们最不共同的祖先。所以，在这种情况下，如果我挑出这两种
of my tree, this would be the least upper bound of those two types.
在我的树中，这将是这两种类型中最小的上界。